ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers, 5780/088
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers
1948-1985.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Tyler, Gus.
5780/088
24 cubic feet
24 linear feet
Records
Contains Gus Tyler's records, documenting his work as Political Director of the ILGWU, writer, editor, and lecturer. In addition to general subject files, records include administrative files, documentation of political activity and speaking engagements, and Tyler's writings, including columns and work for his book Organized Crime in America.
5492906
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
June 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, June 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Biographical / Historical
Gus Tyler, author, commentator, educator, political leader, and official, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU).
Gus Tyler was born in New York in 1911. He attended New York University on a scholarship in the early 1930s, where he became involved in left-wing political activities. After graduating in 1933, Tyler briefly worked as a writer for the Jewish Daily Forward. His sharp intellect and socialist politics caught the attention of ILGWU president David Dubinsky, who hired Tyler to work in the union's Education Department. Tyler left the ILG after a few years to work with the Socialist Party, but returned in the late 1930s. He held a number of positions in the union and in 1945 became Assistant President, which position he held until 1989. Tyler is the author of many articles and books on labor, labor history, economics, and other topics, and for many years has hosted his own radio program on station WEVD in New York. He has also served as an adjunct faculty member at a number of universities and colleges in the U.S., and worked with the ILGWU's successor union, UNITE, as an assistant to the president. Tyler died on June 3, 2011 in Sarasota, Florida.
Scope and Contents
Contains Gus Tyler's records, documenting his work as Political Director of the ILGWU, writer, editor, and lecturer. In addition to general subject files, records include administrative files, documentation of political activity and speaking engagements, and Tyler's writings, including columns and work for his book Organized Crime in America.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/052. ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers
5780/096. ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers
General
"Permanent deposit"
Arrangement
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; Tyler, Gus; Tyler, Gus.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5492906
- Series I. General Files, 1963-1982
  Scope and Contents
  Contains correspondence and materials relating to many organizations in which Gus Tyler had an interest. These files are often indirectly related, at best, to Tyler's activities on behalf of the International Ladies' Garment Workers Union.
  - Adelphi University. Challenge of social change. [folder 1 of 2], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    5/76-12/76. Class taught by Tyler in fall, 1976.
  - Adelphi University. Challenge of social change. [folder 2 of 2], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adelphi University. Political action and political decision making. [folder 1 of 2], 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    1/77-1/78. Class taught by Tyler in spring and fall, 1977.
  - Adelphi University. Political action and political decision making. [folder 2 of 2], 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adelphi University. Writing on social issues, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    6/78-5/79. Class taught by Tyler in fall, 1978.
  - Adelphi University. Writing and problem solving, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    8/79- 11/79. Class taught by Tyler in fall, 1979.
  - Adelphi University. Correspondence about writing class taught by Tyler in 1980, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    2/80-8/81.
  - American Council on Education, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    1/81.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    12/65-4/66. Concerns controversy and eventual split in labor-liberal coalition over the Vietnam War and the 1968 presidential election. Includes correspondence with John P. Roche, John Kenneth Galbraith, Arthur Schlesinger, and others.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    4/66-6/66.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    6/66-2/67.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    2/67-3/67.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    3/67-4/67.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    4/67-5/67.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    5/67-6/67.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings. [folder 1 of 2], 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    6/67.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings. [folder 2 of 2], 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    7/67.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    7/67-9/67.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    9/67-10/67.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    10/67-12/67.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    12/67-1/68.
  - Americans for Democratic Action. General correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    1/68-2/69.
  - American Health Foundation, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    5/80.
  - American Jewish Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    3/79-5/80.
  - American Veterans Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    12/65-5/66.
  - American Veterans Committee, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    5/66-7/66.
  - Anti-Defamation League, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    8/79-10/79.
  - Arthur Andersen and Company. [folder 1 of 2], 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    9/75-4/80. Instruction by Tyler in company's Partner Development Program.
  - Arthur Andersen and Company. [folder 2 of 2], 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bibliography. Lists of sources and references for unknown book written by Tyler, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    8/66. Possibly The Labor Revolution
  - Brandeis University, 1969-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    11/69- 8/77.
  - Calendar, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    2/70-10/72. Includes invitations to various events, excluding speaking engagements, either accepted or rejected by Tyler. Speaking engagements are filed separately.
  - Calendar, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    10/72-4/75.
  - Calendar, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    5/75-11/75.
  - Calendar, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    11/75-2/76.
  - Calendar, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    2/76-5/76.
  - Calendar, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    5/76-12/76.
  - Calendar, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    1/77-6/77.
  - Calendar, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    6/77-11/77.
  - Calendar, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    11/77-9/78.
  - Calendar, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    9/78-6/79.
  - Calendar, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    6/79-2/80.
  - Calendar, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    2/80-11/80.
  - Calendar, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    11/80-6/81.
  - Calendar, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    6/81-12/81. Contains "Status of Black New York 1981" report.
  - Campus Americans for Democratic Action, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    5/66-10/66.
  - Civil rights article, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    7/64-11/67. Concerns chapter written by Tyler in book called The Negro and the American Labor Movement, edited by Julius Jacobson.
  - College Entrance Examination Board. Advisory Panel on Societal Trends and Goals for a Learning Society, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    3/78-8/79.
  - Cornell University. Class taught by Tyler in Industrial and Labor Relations Labor Liberal Arts Program in New York City, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    12/79-5/80.
  - Cornell University. School of Industrial and Labor Relations, general correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    7/78-9/81.
  - Corporate Governance in America. Final Report of the Fifty-Fourth American Assembly [Columbia University], 1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    4/78.
  - Council on Learning [Harvard University, Graduate School of Education], 1979 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    2/79-7/79.
  - Council on Social Work Education, 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    8/77-6/81.
  - Democratic Agenda, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    9/79.
  - Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    4/79.
  - Designers of Harlem. "A Taste of College for High School Dropouts", 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    7/79-11/79. Fashion Institute of Technology educational program.
  - Eastern Regional Conference on Vocational Education, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    5/66.
  - Educational Testing Service. [folder 1 of 3], 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    4/65-3/66.
  - Educational Testing Service. [folder 2 of 3], 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Educational Testing Service. [folder 3 of 3], 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Empire State College, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    3/80.
  - Energy Coalition (Citizen/Labor), 1979 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    3/79.
  - Expenses. [folder 1 of 3], 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    1/74-11/81. These expenses are unrelated to union business. Union-related expenses are filed in Part B.
  - Expenses. [folder 2 of 3], 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Expenses. [folder 3 of 3], 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Family, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    1/74-8/77. Bulletins related to family issues.
  - Four Freedoms Management Corporation, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    6/65-8/66.
  - Fund for the City of New York, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    6/78-9/81.
  - Fund for the City of New York, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    10/81. Transcript of meeting of the Board of Directors.
  - Fund for the City of New York, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    10/81-10/82.
  - Fund for Multinational Management Education. Presentation of Tyler's paper, "Technology Transfer: A Labor View.", 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    1/77-5/78.
  - General Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    9/64-10/67.
  - General Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    10/67-5/68.
  - General Correspondence, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    5/68-7/68.
  - General Correspondence, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    7/68-9/68.
  - General Correspondence, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    9/68-11/68.
  - General Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    11/68-6/70.
  - General Correspondence, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    6/70-8/70.
  - General Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    8/70-3/71.
  - General Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    4/71-1/72.
  - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    1/72-2/72.
  - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    2/72-3/72.
  - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    3/72-5/72.
  - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    6/72-10/72.
  - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    10/72-12/72.
  - General Correspondence, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    12/72-1/78.
  - General Correspondence, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    1/78-8/78.
  - General Correspondence, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    8/78-12/78.
  - General Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    12/78-2/79.
  - General Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    2/79-6/79.
  - General Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    6/79-10/79.
  - General Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    10/79-11/79.
  - General Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    11/79-1/80.
  - General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    1/80-3/80.
  - General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    3/80-7/80.
  - General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    7/80-8/80. Ernest Erber writings sent to Gus Tyler.
  - General Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    8/80-1/81.
  - General Correspondence, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    2/81-6/81.
  - General Correspondence, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    6/81-12/81.
  - Girls' Town, Incorporated, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    11/63.
  - Governor's Task Force on Education, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    3/75.
  - Lois Gray, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    3/71. Paper by Gray, "Republicans and Business: A Marriage of Love or Convenience?"
  - David Hackett, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    12/65. Computer Applications Incorporated. Concerns establishment of planning, programming, and budgeting system in U.S. government.
  - Harvard University Graduate School of Education, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    7/78- 12/78. "Change" Magazine.
  - Histadrut (Israeli Trade Union Federation). [folder 1 of 2], 1967 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Late 1960's? Pamphlets and publications
  - Histadrut (Israeli Trade Union Federation). [folder 2 of 2], 1967 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Hudson Institute, 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    12/78- 12/82.
  - David Hunter, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    1/72-3/72. General Correspondence
  - An Interdisciplinary Attack on Organized Crime, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    5/63. Article by Tyler in a special issue of the Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science on organized crime. The issue, for which Tyler served as special editor, has a full file in Part F.
  - Inform, 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    12/75-11/79. Non- profit research group on workplace safety and public health.
  - Institute for the Future, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    5/80- 11/81.
  - International Rescue Committee. Freedom Award Dinner in honor of George Meany, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    11/64-8/65.
  - International Rescue Committee. Freedom Award Dinner in honor of David Dubinsky, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    5/66-1/67.
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    4/79- 4/81.
  - Joint Council on Economic Education, 1977-1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    1/77-11/81.
  - J.P. Stevens campaign, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    7/78.
  - Labor. Higher Education Conference, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    12/80.
  - Labor. management relations reading lists for high schools, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    9/64.
  - Labor Studies Journal, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    3/81-10/81.
  - League for Industrial Democracy, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    1/75-12/79.
  - The Liberal Crisis, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    10/67-1/68. Article by Tyler in The New Leader.
  - Meetings and other functions. [folder 1 of 3], 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    12/69-12/71. This material, detailing many daily miscellaneous activities, is similar to the calendar file.
  - Meetings and other functions. [folder 2 of 3], 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Meetings and other functions. [folder 3 of 3], 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - National Academy of Sciences. Albert Einstein Memorial, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    1/79-4/79.
  - National Consortium for Public Policy Education, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    3/81.
  - National Urban League, 1974-1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    5/74- 6/81.
  - Christine Neubert (Neubert Ballet Company), 1973 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    5/73-8/73.
  - New York City Board of Education, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - New York State Department of Social Services, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    1/81-3/81.
  - New York Urban League, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    6/74.
  - Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT). [folder 1 of 2], 1964 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    1/64-4/64. Education directors conference. Includes three photographs of Tyler with other participants.
  - Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT). [folder 2 of 2], 1964 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Peace Corps Conference, Washington, D.C. [folder 1 of 2], 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    3/65-6/66.
  - Peace Corps Conference, Washington, D.C. [folder 2 of 2], 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Personal Correspondence. [folder 1 of 2], 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    2/64-12/66. This material is very similar to the General Correspondence file.
  - Personal Correspondence. [folder 2 of 2], 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Marsha Pinkstaff, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    12/72.
  - Mike Quill, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    12/65-3/66. Newspaper articles and other materials dealing with the 1966 New York City transit strike, Mayors Robert Wagner and John Lindsay, and Quill's death in jail.
  - Regional Plan Association (New York metropolitan area). [folder 1 of 2], 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    5/65-6/66.
  - Regional Plan Association (New York metropolitan area). [folder 2 of 2], 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - [Robert F. Kennedy] Service Academy Selection Board. [folder 1 of 2], 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    12/65-1/67.
  - [Robert F. Kennedy] Service Academy Selection Board. [folder 2 of 2], 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - [Robert F. Kennedy] Service Academy Selection Board. [folder 1 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    1/67-3/68.
  - [Robert F. Kennedy] Service Academy Selection Board. [folder 2 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Subcommittee on Selective Service, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    8/65-11/66.
  - Welfare. A Bold New Approach., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    3/70. Excerpt from statement on welfare reform by the AFL-CIO Executive Council.
  - Welfare strike in New York City, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    1/65-3/65.
  - White House Conference. "To Fulfill These Rights." [folder 1 of 2], 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    11/65-6/66.
  - White House Conference. "To Fulfill These Rights." [folder 2 of 2], 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Series II. ILGWU Administration Files, 1955-1982
  Contains correspondence and materials directly related to Gus Tyler's activities within the International Ladies' Garment Workers Union. Includes references to education, training, contract negotiations, and correspondence with members in subordinate organizations.
  - Aging / retirement file, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    8/69-10/69. Material on pensions, social security, and AFL-CIO Social Security Department.
  - Agreements. [folder 1 of 3], 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    1/65-9/66. Correspondence regarding President Dubinsky's approval of various agreements negotiated locally.
  - Agreements. [folder 2 of 3], 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Agreements. [folder 3 of 3], 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Airline expenses, 1973-1981 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    11/73- 11/81.
  - Alba-Waldensian, Incorporated, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    3/65-9/65. Contract negotiations.
  - AFL-CIO. American Federationist, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    10/79-9/80.
  - AFL-CIO. General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    3/80-12/80.
  - AFL-CIO. George Meany Center for Labor Studies, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    7/77.
  - AFL-CIO. Oral history project, 1973-1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    10/73-1/79.
  - AFL-CIO. Research Department, 1978-1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    10/78-8/80.
  - AFL-CIO. Standing Committee on Education, 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    1/79-6/81.
  - Shelley Appleton, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    11/78-8/82. Correspondence with General Secretary-Treasurer Appleton about various issues.
  - Barbizon, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    7/65. Contract negotiations.
  - Berkshire Frocks, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    2/65-1/66. Newspaper clippings and contract negotiations.
  - Theodore Bernstein, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    9/80- 1/81. Head of Benefit Funds Department.
  - Bobbie Brooks. [folder 1 of 2], 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    10/63-11/64. Contract negotiations.
  - Bobbie Brooks. [folder 2 of 2], 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Dr. Emma Bragg, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    4/78-2/79.
  - Burstein Company, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    10/64- 8/65. Contract negotiations.
  - Butte Knitting Mills, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    12/63- 9/65. Contract negotiations.